# **Edward Atkin, Data Scientist**

edwardatkin@edwardatkin.co.uk

+447852264264

Nottinghamshire, United Kingdom

https://www.github.com/eatkin

https://www.edwardatkin.co.uk

# **Profile**

Programmer with a lifelong affinity for digital development. Cultivated a versatile skill set that spans web development, data science, game development and beyond. Recently graduated from Le Wagon's intensive Data Science Bootcamp, gaining experience developing individual and group projects. Background in brewing and developing award winning beers, now dedicated to a career in data science and digital innovation.

# **Education**

# Data Science, Le Wagon April 2023-October 2023 | Remote

- Part time coding bootcamp covering Python, SQL, Statistical Analysis, Machine Learning, Deep Learning and MLOps
- Developed a variety of individual and group projects

# BSci Mathematical Physics, University of Nottingham

# September 2011-July 2015

- Applied complex mathematical theories to real-world scenarios
- Completed a scientific computing project predicting probabilities of particles in different potentials using MATLAB

# **Technical Skills**

### **Programming Languages**

Python, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, SQL

## **Data Science and Analytics**

Web scraping, data visualisation, machine learning modelling, deep neural networks, statistical learning and modelling

### **Tools and Technologies**

VSCode, Vim, Git/Github, Jupyter Notebook, ZShell, Google Cloud Platform

# **Professional Experience**

## Head Brewer, Matlock Brewing Company Ltd April 2015-present

- Led all aspects of brewing production from recipe development to production for a small, family-run business
- Developed award winning recipes, including one utilising heritage barley variety Chevallier
- Managed market stalls and events, working directly with customers to promote the brand

### Development Team Lead, Date & Game

### April 2021-May 2023

- Game developer for a small startup creating a dating app with multiplayer game integration
- Built robust, modular systems supporting online multiplayer gameplay as the basis for a variety of games
- Worked with artists, game designers and app developers to integrate the game into the app
- Supported new developers in learning the codebase and working with the systems

# **Projects**

For further details and to explore my projects, visit https://www.edwardatkin.co.uk Reddit Sentiment Analysis

#### 2023

- Group project working in a team of 5 to analyse the sentiment of Reddit comments
- Developed an API using FastAPI and created a user interface using Streamlit Horse Racing Predictor

### 2023

- Horse racing predictor built from data sourcing through to model training and deployment
- Continuous monitoring of model predictions to find meaningful ways to interpret results
- Automation systems using Shell scripting to run daily data collection and predictions Coding Heaven (Blog)

### 2023

• Authored *Coding Heaven*, a blog to share my experiences of programming and data science concepts in a fun and entertaining way

# Other Minds

#### 2021

- Open world 2d platformer project with unique mechanics allowing the player to control any entity within the game
- Developed over two years as a solo developer
- Worked on game design, programming, artwork and music